哈喽呀
Hello there
我叫Gavin，字幕翻译给虫，欢迎观看这期视频，很奇怪吧这期在我家
My name's Gavin, and welcome to this episode of the Slow Mo Guys very oddly presented from my living room
之前我做过一个视频叫“相机慢动作下是怎样工作的”，反响不错
A while ago, I made a video called   "How a camera works in slow-mo" and the response was great
所以我自然想做一期电视在慢动作下是怎样工作的
so I thought a good natural progression to that video would be how a TV works in slow-mo
这是一台85寸的LCD电视，无论我用它玩什么
This is an 85 inch LCD TV and whenever I'm playing something on it
或者看什么节目，我的眼睛和大脑都被欺骗了，让我以为
or watching something on it, my eyes and brain are being misled and tricked, giving me the illusion
我在看运动的物体，但实际上我看到的是
of watching a moving object when in fact I'm just watching
一连串静止画面，只是显示得非常快
several still images just shown to me very, very fast
比如如果我看的是电影，我一秒会看到24张图片
If I'm watching a film, I'm being shown 24 images every second
我的眼睛仿佛在看移动物体，而实际上我每秒在看24张静止画面
and to my eyes that looks like I'm looking at a moving object, when in fact I'm looking at 24 individual pictures
如果我在玩游戏，那就是每秒30或者60帧
If I'm playing a game, it's the same except maybe 30 to 60 frames a second
如果是在用电脑，帧数可能会上百
and if I'm on a PC it could be hundreds
这帮屁吸优越狗
PC Master Race
但是电视实际上不能一下子显示一整张图，1/24秒后再显示下一张
But a TV like this is actually incapable of showing you one image, and then a twenty-fourth of a second later
just switching all at once to the next image
而要演示这点，我要使用老式的CRT显示器
And to illustrate this next point, I'm gonna use a very old, and very crap CRT TV
这是射频线
That stands for cathode ray tube
如果你们注意过的话
If you've ever seen one of these filmed
你们可能发现摄像机里的电视和我们眼睛看到的不太一样
you may notice that it looks slightly different on camera than it does to your eye
你看
Look at that
会这样闪的原因是这台摄像机快门速度
The reason it looks like this is because the shutter speed of this camera
和显示器的刷新速度不同步
is out of sync with the refresh rate of this screen
每一帧图像是从上到下形成
The frame is constructed from the top to the bottom
每秒很多次——美国这里是60次，即刷新率60Hz
multiple times per second -- that's 60 times in the US, 60 Hertz
我很久以前已经用V2511高速摄像机准备好一些片段
I've prepared for you some high-speed footage that I shot a long time ago on the V2511
其中包含这个CRT显示器，和后面这个LCD，还有些其他的
of this screen and this screen and some others
当中不少是Dan在NES上玩超级玛丽的菜鸡录像
A lot of it is Dan playing Super Mario on the NES extremely badly
这里是电视和喵星人在每秒25帧下的画面
Here's the TV and the cat played back at 25
视频里的速度和实际时间是一样的
This is how it would be perceived in real time
然后是每秒1600帧，你能清楚看到扫描线从上到下在扫描
and now at 1600 frames a second you can actually see the scan line moving from the top to the bottom
你能注意到在CRT显示器里，只有一横条像素会亮
You'll notice that on a CRT screen, it's only the active line of pixels that's bright
而视觉暂留会让你看到一幅完整画面
and your persistence of vision will actually build that into a complete image
我特么快被晃瞎了
It's messing with my eyes this
跟迪厅似的
It's like a dance floor
哎呦我去我这第一个怪都没跳过去
Aghhh... Didn't even make it past the first guy
接下来放慢到每秒2500帧
Slowed all the way down to 2500 frames a second
你现在能看清每一帧是从上到下形成的
you can now differentiate each individual frame being built from top to bottom
这需要非常高速的摄像机才能看清这个“从上到下”的过程
It takes an extremely fast camera to see that each frame is built line by line from top to bottom
而想要看清每一横条从左到右的形成，则需要更更更高速的摄像机
but it takes an even faster camera to see that each line is drawn from left to right
放慢到每秒28500帧，我们勉强能感觉到这个“从左到右”的过程，但这还不够
Slow down to 28,500 frames a second we're now seeing glimpses of that, but we do need to go even slower
现在减慢到118000帧每秒
This is now 118,000 frames a second
我把数据放上面供你们参考
I'm going to put the stats up for you here
你可以看到对应的实际时间，也能看清一条线是怎样
so you can see the actual amount of time that it took, and you can see now that the line is being drawn
从左到右画过去的
from left to right on the screen
现在是每秒146000帧
Now a 146,000 frames a second
你们感受下现在有多慢了
To gain perspective on just how slow this actually is
你们看下面这时间
You can see the exact time I shot this.
这是小时，刚过午夜，0点23分41秒
So this is hours, it was just past midnight, 23 minutes 41 seconds
然后是十分之一秒，百分之一秒，千分之一秒，也就是一毫秒，然后接下来
This is a tenth of a second, a hundredth of a second, one thousandth of a second or a millisecond, and then over here
是万分之一秒
you've got a ten thousandth of a second
然后十万分之一秒，然后百万分之一秒，也就是一微秒
A hundred thousandth of a second, and this unit here is the millionth of a second or a microsecond
我们现在是每秒38万帧
We are now at 380,000 frames a second as our recording frame rate
这是迄今为止本频道用到的最高的帧数了
That is the highest frame rate we've ever shot so far on this channel and using this information
于是你们能发现，CRT显示器能在38万分之一秒内画完马里奥大叔的胡子
here's a little bonus fact: a CRT screen can draw Mario's moustache in less than a 380,000th of a second
你说这胡子长的多快
That is some seriously fast facial hair
如果你奇怪为啥画面这么模糊，那是因为这显示器分辨率只有
And if you're wondering why this footage looks extremely mucky and blurry, it's because the resolution is only
256x128，如果放到4k画面里，它只有……
256 by 128 which plunked into a 4k frame is...
这么大
this big
之前那是标准的CRT分辨率（此处存疑），这是4k显示器，即
That CRT screen is standard def. This is a 4k screen which means it's
3840x2160像素，超过八百万像素。所以你们想想这个点是处理图像的能力
3840 by 2160 pixels that's over 8 million pixels. So think of the processing power that this TV
要求它更新一幅那么大的画面
has to have to update an image
每秒还要更新那么多次。首先你会注意到现代LCD显示器
that big for that many times every second. The first thing you'll notice about a modern LCD screen is that it's
不是只点亮某一横条的像素
not only the active line of pixels that retains brightness
它会保持整个图像全亮，所以实际上在扫描线从上往下走时你能看到整幅图像
It's the entire image, so you can actually see the full image as each scanline passes down the screen
这是Xbox One开启启动画面
This is every frame of the startup sequence on an Xbox One
我还录了一段我玩光环的视频，不是想让你知道慢动作下自己瞄准有多菜
I also recorded myself playing game of Halo nothing to make you feel worse about your performance
我还录了一段我玩光环的视频，不是想让你知道慢动作下自己有多菜
than watching your lousy aim in slow-mo look at that
其实想想你在玩游戏的时候，电视实际上是这样工作的还是挺有意思的
It's crazy to think that when you're playing Halo. This is actually what is happening on your TV
你要是能看这么快的话，你就有可能打过五五开了
If only you could see it as speed your aim would be incredible
所以讲真我有时候看电视看睡着了，感觉真的好伤心
It honestly makes me feel bad when I fall asleep watching TV
电视君那边忙得不行每秒刷新上千万像素点
Knowing that this TV is doing all this intensive work changing literally tens of millions of pixels
而你却在睡大觉不看它
every second and there's no one there watching it
有趣的是到了iPhone，它永远是保持竖屏模式从上往下刷新
Here's a fun fact the same applies to an iPhone except it's in portrait mode
所以当你用iPhone把屏幕横过来看视频的时候
so if you're watching a video in landscape mode on your iPhone
你的画面其实是从左往右或者从右往左刷新的，取决于你怎么转的手机
you're actually getting updates from left to right or right to left depending on which way you flipped it and
这刚好印证了肉眼是看不到刷新方向的
That just proved to me that you can't see the Refresh direction with your naked eye
因为我完全不知道每次我用iPhone看B站视频的时候
because I had no idea whenever I was watching a YouTube video on my iPhone that the screen
手机刷新的方向竟然改变了
was updating in a completely different direction. I'm not sure if this is the case for all smart phones
我不确定所有智能手机都这样，但至少这个视频里我的iPhone 7 plus是这样的
but it's certainly the case on an iPhone 7 plus which is what I film this on
我们我们刚说了电视的运动图像的显示方法，接下来是
So we've talked about one illusion of TV's the illusion of movement the second illusion
颜色的显示方法。我还需要一个相机
I want to talk about is the illusion of color for this next part. I'm going to need a second camera. Here's one
就你了，哈喽啊，所以想要贴近了看电视，我得把相机焦距
That's you hello you so in order to film this screen extremely close. I want to set my focus
调到最近的距离
the minimum possible distance
差不多这里了。当我慢慢向前靠近屏幕的时候，图像越来越清晰
So it's sort of like right here now. Set to my minimum focus. As I slowly moved towards the screen it becomes sharper
你会在某刻发现一些很奇怪的闪烁图案
and you will then at the last minute see a very odd looking pattern
而这是相机想要解析屏幕表面每一个像素点造成的
And what you're seeing there is an effect caused by the camera this camera trying to resolve
individual pixels on the surface of this screen
而我再靠近屏幕，这个效应就消失了
As I push further forward the effect disappears and
图像再次失焦，因为我已经比
Everything goes out of focus that's because I'm now beyond
这个镜头最小焦距还要近了，这个长度大概这么大
the minimum focal distance of this lens which is about what it's about they're
还不够近。上微距镜头！
Not close enough. In order to get closer, I'm gonna need a macro lens
来了！随着我继续靠近，焦距又对回来了
Here's one as I approach the white and everything starts to become in focus
你会发现白色其实没那么白了，我觉得得再近些
You can see that white isn't so white anymore it looks like I have to go closer even than that
还好我还能放大五倍
thankfully I can go all the way to five times magnification
而从这开始
Now one thing from this point
我肯定得用三脚架了，因为我胳膊可没那么稳
I am definitely gonna need a tripod because there's no way my arms are sturdy enough to hold this in place
但我先试试用胳膊好让你们体会下现在放大了多少倍
But I'll just ease it in just to show you the level of magnification we're talking about now
好吧这么近就完全不一样了诶。我去拿三脚架。来了！
Well this close it's a different story altogether, I'm gonna get a tripod. Here's one
真累啊这活
What a mission this is
我们现在已经近到往镜头上吹气都能让画面产生明显晃动了
We're so close up right now that I can actually disturb this image by blowing on the lens
我们能看到子像素点了，每个像素有三个子像素
We're now looking at the sub pixel level a pixel is made up of three sub pixels
红绿蓝，就是RGB，你们以前可能听过
red green and blue RGB you may have heard that before and
通过不同程度的点亮不同子像素来显示不同颜色
This creates the illusion of different colors by dimming and brightening different sub pixels to different intensities
这个屏幕能显示上百万种颜色。
this screen can create the illusion of literally millions of different colors
三个都亮时显示白色
When all three are lit to full brightness you get white
三个都变暗时图像就慢慢变灰直到变黑。所以当绿色变暗，红色蓝色变亮
When all three dim you go through gray all the way down to black so if green dims away and red and blue are still
就会得到品色。这就是颜色的产生。所以每次你看电视
lit then you go into magenta purple. That's all very and that's how the colors are made so every time on your TV
当你看到白色图像，你看的是无数红色、绿色、蓝色的小灯
You're looking at a white image. You're looking at tons of blue green and red lights
它们太小了所以看上去就像白色一样
They're just so small. They look like white to your eye
得到白色之前，你能看到红绿蓝变成了黄青品三色
Before you get white red green and blue blurs into yellow cyan and magenta
因为我把相机挪了挪，让它失焦了
And that's what happens here when I move the screen slightly out of focus
第一次这么近距离看我这系列的慢动作视频，我要吐了
This is too close to watch the Slow Mo Guys video. I might vomit
CRT情况也一样
It's the same situation
只是像素块大点
Just entire blocks and they're bigger
我之前提过，典型LCD显示器是用CCFL点亮的
As I mentioned before this is a 4k LCD screen which a while back were typically lit by CCFLs or
全称叫冷阴极荧光灯管，也就是说整个屏幕是被荧光灯点亮的
A cold cathode fluorescent lamp which means the entire panel is backlit by fluorescent tubes
而现在呢
Nowadays
它们是用LED灯点亮的
They are backlit by LEDs
所以才叫“LED电视”。而LED比LCD的好处在于
This is why this would actually be marketed as an LED TV. The benefit of LED screens over CCFL screens
它们更薄
is that they're a lot thinner
现在我要把相机挪到黑色的部分。有趣的是尽管该区域是黑色的
Now I'm going to point it at where some black text is. Now interestingly even though this area is black
因为所有的子像素都暗下去了，它们仍然是有背景光的，一会给你们看
Because all the sub pixels are dimmed. They are still in fact backlit. Let me show you that right now
当我们挪到这时，抱歉因为曝光度问题画面噪声有点高
now you can see as we push in here you have to pardon noise
for an extremely high ISO to get this shot through a macro lens
你能看见液晶显示器上的暗的像素点
You can see even the dimmed pixels part of the liquid crystal
在尽量挡住后面的光穿过
display as it's now trying to block all light from penetrating through
但它肯定不能完全挡住，总会有点亮，所以这就是
but it's still a backlit pixel, and that's one of the fundamental
LCD显示器的缺点之一。你能在LCD显示器上
limitations of an LCD screen. You can see this effect on an LCD screen
看到这一点，当你看一幅几乎全黑的图的时候
in the credits of a film because got almost completely black image
因为上面还有白色的字
But because there's white text the entire
所以就必须有背光，导致总有光会从黑色像素点漏出来
Backlight has to be on to display the white which means light will leak out from the black pixels
也就是说这不是真的黑色
Which means it's not true black
最近一项新技术也越来越流行了，叫作OLED屏幕
There is another technology that's becoming much more common these days and that is an OLED-screen
全称有机发光二极管。我的确想做LCD和OLED屏幕的对比
Organic light-emitting diode. I did want to include a comparison between an LCD panel and an OLED panel
但我没有OLED电视，不过还好在我录制这期视频过程当中
But I didn't actually have an OLED TV and by sheer luck right in the middle of me shooting all this footage
LG联系到了我，给我提供了一款OLED电视来做测评
LG got in touch and offered to supply me with an OLED TV for the purpose of making this video
非常感谢LG。所以一起来看看吧！
which I really appreciate, thanks, LG. What are we going to take a look at it?
这是LG的77寸OLED电视。OLED的工作原理是每个像素点
This is a 77 inch LG OLED TV. The way OLED technology works is that each pixel is
会根据电压来自身发光
Self-illuminating depending on how much voltage is passing through it
所以电视本身不需要全局的背光
which means there's no global backlight on the TV
每个像素点亮度单独受控
Each pixel is individually in control of
而不是靠背光，使得我们在用高感光度
how bright it is and it's not being lit from behind and that means when we go to our high ISO
实验时——就像对LCD做的一样——当屏幕出现一块黑色的时候
experiment just like we've done the LCD that when there's an area of black on the screen
所有像素点都是关闭的
All of those pixels are off
你能看到当我把光标挪过来时，这些子像素点又亮起来
And you can see here where I'm putting my cursor in front of the lens you can see each sub pixel lighting up and then
光标挪走时又全灭
completely turning off when it goes away
这项技术使得显示更暗的黑色、与更薄的屏幕成为可能
This technology means much deeper blacks and the possibility of a very thin screen
所以就这样啦，电视在慢动作下的工作原理
And there you have it a brief explanation of how a TV works in slow-mo
喜欢记得点关注
If you found that video interesting chances are
投币、收藏、分享一波
you might find some other videos interesting on this channel
这个YouTuber频道名叫The Slow Mo Guys
So make sure you *boop* [subscribe] and once you booped feel free to check out our *kneet* [merchandise].
感谢观看
It's just there. Thank you very much for watching
哈哈哈怎么样我这个时机掐的
That was good timing wasn't it? *laughs*
刚好让电视放烟花
TV timed out and now there's fireworks